MOHAMD DORRA

Software Engineer Syrian | 1985 Istanbul, Turkey mhd.durrah@gmail.com +90 (535) 783 7663





A Software Engineer with 9+ years of industry experience with Java, Web, and enterprise development, Resourceful in managing all aspects of the requirement analysis, suggesting technology-based solutions, design, development, testing, deployment and implementation of business solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Amadeus IT Group / Software Development Engineer MAY 2017 - Present / ISTANBUL

- Loyalty Community Project (LOY) Core Modules and Architecture.
- Stabilizing and optimizing Batch processing jobs.
- Software Principles and Design Patterns trainer.

Kancy Smart Home / Software Development Engineer NOV 2014 - Apr 2017 / ISTANBUL

- Leading the Analysis, Design and Development of Kancy Smart homes SaaS platform with Spring Framework, Eclipse Runtime, ActiveMQ, Cassandra and Hibernate on AWS.
- Integration of Apache ActiveMQ with the custom OSGi runtime to achieve real-time communication and monitoring.
- Development of Android client application including MQTT communications,
 UI customization and database abstraction.

Invest4all / Software Development Engineer

JAN 2011 - MAY 2013 / DAMASCUS

 Contribute in System Analysis and Development of business process streamliner with EJB, web services and Hibernate in backend, JSF and Primefaces components for frontend.

EDUCATION

Faculty of IT / Bachelor of Computer Science **2004 - 2010 DAMASCUS UNIVERSITY** Bachelor of Computer Science in Artificial Intelligence

Software Architecture, Java SE Spring, Spring Boot JPA, Hibernate EJB, JSF, Primefaces REST API, OSGi, Git Kafka, Hadoop, Spark Team Work, Work Ethic

English: Excellent RWS
Turkish: Mid RWS

Arabic: Native

Mr. Tammam Fadel

Invest4all project manager tammam.fadel.ca@gmail.com

+1 514 967 7104

More upon request